Guide to the Robert Fitzgerald Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1902-1986; Series I; 22.52; (54 boxes)
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Other Family Correspondence
      - To and From Sarah Morgan Fitzgerald
        - Other correspondence, 1948, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1852)
      - To and From Ughetta Fitzgerald
        - Fitzgerald, Barnaby, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1853)
        - Fitzgerald, Benedict, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1854)
        - Maxwell, William, 1960 May 20 (Box 51, Folder 1855)
      - To and From Eleanor Green
        - Fitzgerald, Edward, 1940 Feb 6 (Box 51, Folder 1856)
        - Stuart, Agnes, 1938-45 (Box 51, Folder 1857)
        - Stuart, Elizabeth, 1936 Aug 5 (Box 51, Folder 1858)
      - To and From Francis Stuart Low
        - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1859)
      - To and From Sara McHugh
        - Fitzgerald, Anne Montague Stuart, 1911, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1860)
      - To and From Betsy Rahn
        - "Dad", 1929 Mar 31 (Box 51, Folder 1861)
      - To and From Agnes Stuart
        - Fitzgerald, Anne Montague Stuart, 1909-13, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1862-1864)
        - Fitzgerald, Barnaby, 1959-67, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1865)
          Includes drawings
        - Fitzgerald, Benedict, 1957 May 25 (Box 52, Folder 1866)
        - Fitzgerald, Catherine, 1970, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1867)
        - Fitzgerald family, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1868)
        - Fitzgerald, Maria, 1970 Mar 8 (Box 52, Folder 1869)
        - Fitzgerald, Michael, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1870)
        - Fitzgerald, Sarah Morgan, 1947-66 (Box 52, Folder 1871-1872)
        - Fitzgerald, Ughetta ("Hugh"), 1950-70, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1873)
        - Green, Eleanor, 1936-45, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1874)
        - Low, Francis Stuart, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1875)
        - Stuart, Charles G., 1944 Feb. 16 (Box 52, Folder 1876)
        - [Stuart?], Elizabeth, 1929 May 30 (Box 52, Folder 1877)
        - Stuart, Gerry, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 1878)
        - Stuart, Jack, 1959, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1879)
        - Stuart, John, 1929-55 (Box 52, Folder 1880)
        - Stuart, "Ginnie", 1957 Nov 19 (Box 52, Folder 1881)
        - Stuart, Marie, 1929-44 (Box 52, Folder 1882)
        - Stuart, Nora Anne, 1939-70, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1883)
        - [Stuart?], Viegne, 1970, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1884)
        - Other correspondence, 1913-21, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1885)
        - Empty envelopes, 1912-64 (Box 52, Folder 1886)
      - To and From John McHugh Stuart
        - Fitzgerald, Anne M., 1903 (Box 52, Folder 1887)
        - McHugh, Sara A., 1949 Jun 19 (Box 52, Folder 1888)
      - To and From Marie F. Stuart
        - Fitzgerald, Arthur Michael, 1944-47 (Box 52, Folder 1889)
        - [Rahn?], Betsy, 1934 Jan 6 (Box 52, Folder 1890)
        - Empty envelope, 1950 Jul 9 (Box 52, Folder 1891)
    - Third Party Correspondence
      - To and From Arthur Fitzgerald
        - Cochran, John R., 1928 Oct (Box 52, Folder 1895)
        - Henry and Kyer, 1905 Aug 31 (Box 52, Folder 1896)
      - To Barnaby Fitzgerald
        - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1970-72 (Box 52, Folder 1897)
      - To and From Benedict Fitzgerald
        - Harvard University, 1970-71 (Box 52, Folder 1898)
        - Salaun, Jean-Michel, 1970 Aug (Box 52, Folder 1899)
        - Other Correspondence, 1959-84, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1900)
      - To and From Catherine Fitzgerald
        - ----, Ana Marie, 1975, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1901)
        - Other correspondence, 1975 Sep (Box 52, Folder 1902)
      - To Edward J. Fitzgerald
        - The Choate School, 1929 Jul (Box 52, Folder 1902a)
      - To and From Maria Juliana Fitzgerald
        - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1959-62 (Box 52, Folder 1903)
      - To and From Penelope Laurans Fitzgerald
        - Agoos, Julie, 1986 Aug (Box 52, Folder 1904)
        - American Academy, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 1905)
        - [Baker], Barbara, 1984 Dec 10 (Box 52, Folder 1906)
        - Choate Rosemary Hall, 1985 Feb (Box 52, Folder 1907)
        - Goldensohn, Barry, 1983 Dec 30 (Box 52, Folder 1908)
        - Goldensohn, Lorrie, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1909)
        - Homick, Marcia, 1980-84 (Box 52, Folder 1910)
        - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1984 Nov 29 (Box 52, Folder 1911)
        - Kiely, Robert, 1980 Nov 13 (Box 52, Folder 1912)
        - Kolker, Heather, 1984 Oct 16 (Box 52, Folder 1913)
        - Laughlin, Ann, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 1914)
        - Laughlin, James, 1986 Jul 17 (Box 53, Folder 1915)
          Includes letter to Laughlin from Alfred Ogle
        - Levin, Richard, 1985 Jan 11 (Box 53, Folder 1916)
        - Lieberman, [Natalie?], n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1917)
        - Maxwell, Emily, 1982 Mar 14 (Box 53, Folder 1918)
        - Mendelson, Edward, 1979 Jun (Box 53, Folder 1919)
        - Ogle, Alfred, 1986 Jul 23 (Box 53, Folder 1920)
        - Paulson, Barbara, 1979 May 24 (Box 53, Folder 1921)
        - Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1976 Sep 2 (Box 53, Folder 1922)
        - St. John, George Jr., 1984 Nov 3 (Box 53, Folder 1923)
        - Satterthwaite, Isabel, 1978 May 28 (Box 53, Folder 1924)
        - Shaw, Robert, 1984 Aug 24 (Box 53, Folder 1925)
        - Simpson, Eileen B., 1976, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 1926)
        - Wilentz, Ted, 1978 Nov 16 (Box 53, Folder 1927)
        - Other correspondence, 1975-82 (Box 53, Folder 1928)
      - To and From Robert E. Fitzgerald
        - The Choate School, 1928 (Box 53, Folder 1928a)
        - Culver Military Academy, 1928 Aug 15 (Box 53, Folder 1929)
        - McIntyre, Frank J., 1906-07 (Box 53, Folder 1930)
        - Mack, William B., 1905-06 (Box 53, Folder 1931)
        - Neal, Thomas A., 1905 (Box 53, Folder 1932)
        - [Empty folder] (Box 53, Folder 1933)
        - Santa Clara College, 1902 Aug 4 (Box 53, Folder 1934)
        - Springfield High School, 1925 Feb 23 (Box 53, Folder 1935)
        - Other correspondence, 1904-07, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1936)
      - To and From Sarah Morgan Fitzgerald
        - [Baker], Barbara, 1966 May 25 (Box 53, Folder 1937)
        - Culton, Morgan, Britain and White, 1957-58 (Box 53, Folder 1938)
        - Encyclopedia Britannica, Inc., 1966 (Box 53, Folder 1939)
        - Fergusson, Peggy, n.y. Apr 29 (Box 53, Folder 1940)
        - Gordon, Caroline, 1970, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1941)
        - Longstreth, Clara, 1965 Apr 12 (Box 53, Folder 1942)
        - Mills, M. (Marguerite), 1965, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1943)
        - Morgan, Connie, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1944)
        - New Republic, 1952-53 (Box 53, Folder 1945)
        - O'Connor, Flannery, 1951, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1946)
        - Other correspondence, 1980, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1947)
      - To and From Ughetta Fitzgerald
        - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1959-73, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1948)
      - To and From Eleanor Green
        - Mumford, ----, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1949)
        - St. John, Clara, 1936 Jul 25 (Box 53, Folder 1950)
        - Walker and Latton, 1945 Sep 17 (Box 53, Folder 1951)
        - ----, "Jay", n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1952)
      - To and From Sara McHugh
        - Unidentified, 1930 May 11 (Box 53, Folder 1953)
      - To and From Agnes Stuart
        - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1952 Aug 18 (Box 53, Folder 1954)
        - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1964 May 1 (Box 53, Folder 1955)
        - Cathedral of the Immaculate Conception, 1916-33, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1956-1957)
        - Culver Summer Schools, 1928 Aug 20 (Box 53, Folder 1958)
        - Fitts, Dudley, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 1959)
        - [Forgus?], Mary, 1936 Jan (Box 53, Folder 1960)
        - Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1960 (Box 53, Folder 1961)
        - McDaniel, Hattie, 1948 Feb 27 (Box 53, Folder 1962)
        - Obear, Julia, 1930-44 (Box 53, Folder 1963)
        - Obear, Legare Hill Bowles, 1935-46, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1964)
        - St. John, George Jr., 1957 Jun 2 (Box 53, Folder 1965)
        - Sharp, Alexander; Sharp, Cornelia, 1943-60 (Box 53, Folder 1966)
        - United States. Office of the President, 1962 Jan 16 (Box 53, Folder 1967)
        - United States. Post Office Dept., 1952 Aug 18 (Box 53, Folder 1968)
        - United States. Veterans Administration, 1943 Dec 22 (Box 53, Folder 1969)
        - Wiegard, Rose Estelle, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1970)
        - Wooster, Katherine Stuart, 1945-68, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1971)
        - Wooster, Samuel [Stuart?], 1940-45, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1972)
        - Other correspondence, 1914-67, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1973-1974)
        - First name only, 1933-70, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1975)
        - Unidentified, 1907-52, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1976)
      - To and From John Stuart
        - Springfield Marine Bank, 1960 Jun 15 (Box 53, Folder 1977)
      - To and From [Marie?] Stuart
        - Springfield Marine Bank, 1964 Dec 30 (Box 53, Folder 1978)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - To Doubleday and Company, Inc.
      - Coward, McCann & Geoghegan, Inc., 1982 Jul 12 (Box 54, Folder 1979)
      - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1981 May 22 (Box 54, Folder 1980)
    - From English-Speaking Union
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1931 Nov 18 (Box 54, Folder 1981)
        Includes letters from English- Speaking Union to Mrs. Arthur L. Goodhart and others
    - To and From Farrar, Straus & Giroux
      - American Center of P.E.N., 1981 Oct 20 (Box 54, Folder 1982)
      - Baird, Sarah, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 1983)
      - Russell & Volkening, Inc., 1953 Jun 19 (Box 54, Folder 1984)
    - To Dudley Fitts
      - [Fergusson], Francis, [1939] Feb 14 (Box 54, Folder 1985)
      - Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1937-41 (Box 54, Folder 1986)
      - Library of Congress, 1940 Mar 30 (Box 54, Folder 1987)
      - Sitwell, Edith, 1949 Dec 5 (Box 54, Folder 1988)
      - [Sly?], Allan, 1939 Aug 5 (Box 54, Folder 1989)
      - Sullivan, A. M. [(Aloysius Michael)?], 1939 May 10 (Box 54, Folder 1990)
      - [Swan], Emma, 1935, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1991)
      - [Valentine?], Jean, 1967 Jul 7 (Box 54, Folder 1992)
      - ----, Jack, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1993)
      - Unidentified, 1937, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 1994)
    - To and From Harvard University
      - Engel, Monroe, 1973 Jul 30 (Box 54, Folder 1995)
      - Laurie, Peter, 1975 Nov 5 (Box 54, Folder 1996)
      - Lowell, Robert, 1973, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 1997)
      - Lubin, Peter, 1966 Sep (Box 54, Folder 1998)
      - Salaün, Jean-Michel, 1970 Jun 15 (Box 54, Folder 1999)
      - Strand, Mark, 1980 Jan 24 (Box 54, Folder 2000)
      - Stritch, Thomas, 1964 Dec 11 (Box 54, Folder 2001)
    - To McIntosh, McKee and Dodds
      - Miscellaneous, 1974-75 (Box 54, Folder 2002)
    - To and From Jacques Maritain
      - Hanover Bank (New York, N.Y.), 1960 Jan (Box 54, Folder 2003)
    - To and From Eileen B. Simpson
      - Howe, Irving, 1979 Feb 12 (Box 54, Folder 2004)
      - Tate, Caroline, 1954 Mar 28 (Box 54, Folder 2005)
    - From United States. Veterans Administration
      - Durand, Margaret A., 1935 Feb 2 (Box 54, Folder 2006)
      - Owens, S. Logan, 1938 Jun 29 (Box 54, Folder 2007)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Adams, Sallie to John Nims, 1977 Feb 20 (Box 54, Folder 2008)
      - Atlantic Monthly Press to Houghton Mifflin and Company, 1968 Jul 8 (Box 54, Folder 2009)
      - Auden, W. H. (Wyston Hugh) to Mr. Lowrie, 1964 Sep 28 (Box 54, Folder 2010)
      - Baird, Sarah to Lovell Thompson, 1972 May 25 (Box 54, Folder 2011)
      - Broad, C. D. (Charlie Dunbar) to Mr. Hanford, 1933 Feb 20 (Box 54, Folder 2012)
      - Clayton, Thomas to A. Dwight Culler, 1974 Oct 19 (Box 54, Folder 2013)
      - Coward, McCann & Geoghegan, Inc. to James Agee Trust, 1981 Dec 11 (Box 54, Folder 2014)
      - Davison, Peter to Bollingen Foundation, 1965 Jun 24 (Box 54, Folder 2015)
      - Dowson, Ernest to "Smithers", [1897 Oct 26?] (Box 54, Folder 2016)
      - Drake, Robert to Mrs. Edward O'Connor, 1966 Feb 13 (Box 54, Folder 2017)
      - Duncan, Harry to Houghton Mifflin and Company, 1964 Jan 28 (Box 54, Folder 2018)
      - Flye, James Harold to "David", 1967 Jun 10 (Box 54, Folder 2019)
      - Graham, Alethea to Mrs. Albert Erlaude, 1932 Mar 8 (Box 54, Folder 2020)
      - Haferd, Margaret to Ann McGarrell, 1973 Jul 31 (Box 54, Folder 2021)
      - Headlam, John to John E. J. Fanshawe, 1929 Aug 27 (Box 54, Folder 2022)
      - Houston First Federal Savings and Loan Association to S.A.L. Morgan, 1952 Oct 20 (Box 54, Folder 2023)
      - Ignatow, David to "Debbie", 1973 Mar 19 (Box 54, Folder 2024)
      - International Committee on English in the Liturgy to Templegate Publishers, 1966 Jan 26 (Box 54, Folder 2025)
      - Johns Hopkins University Press to Frank J. Nisetich, 1979 Aug 17 (Box 54, Folder 2026)
      - Klein, O. to R. Oppenheimer, 1950 Apr 21 (Box 54, Folder 2027)
      - Kreymborg, Alfred to Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1936 Aug 14 (Box 54, Folder 2028)
      - Lall, Raganath to unidentified, [1957] (Box 54, Folder 2029)
      - Laughlin, James to Annie Dillard, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 2030)
      - Levant, Daniel to Anne Freegood, 1966 Jan 27 (Box 54, Folder 2031)
      - [McIn...], Frank to Francis J. Byrne, 1907 Oct (Box 54, Folder 2032)
      - MacKaye, Percy to MacMillan Company, 1939 Nov 18 (Box 54, Folder 2033)
      - Murphy, William M. to Christopher [Murphy?], 1980 Dec 2 (Box 54, Folder 2034)
      - [Nichols, Robert?] to Queenie Dorothy Lewis, 1931 Nov (Box 54, Folder 2035)
      - [Padilla?] to "Miss Ach", n.d. (Box 54, Folder 2035a)
      - Parker House to The Saturday Club, 1980 Aug 27 (Box 54, Folder 2036)
      - The Pembroke Magazine to Archibald MacLeish, 1974 Oct 23 (Box 54, Folder 2037)
      - Phelps, Robert to "David", 1967 May 24 (Box 54, Folder 2038)
      - Piel, Gerard to Andrew Heiskell, 1978 Sep 7 (Box 54, Folder 2039)
      - Raizis, M. Byron to BOA Editions, 1981 Mar 25 (Box 54, Folder 2040)
      - Schwarzbart, Elias M. to The New Republic, 1977 Aug 11 (Box 54, Folder 2041)
      - Taylor, Charles to Indiana University Press, 1961 Feb 18 (Box 54, Folder 2041a)
      - Taylor, Roderick to John Frederick Nims, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 2042)
      - Thomas Cook & Son, Ltd. to Antionette Milet, 1931 Dec 16 (Box 54, Folder 2043)
      - Vanderbilt, Robert to Miss Anderson, 1953 Oct 25 (Box 54, Folder 2044)
      - Warner, Charles K. to unidentified, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 2045)
      - Wesleyan University to Robert Lescher, 1963 May 30 (Box 54, Folder 2046)
      - Zahner, Louis to Harcourt, Brace Co., 1939 (Box 54, Folder 2047)
        Includes transcriptions of letters from Donald Davidson, John Stuart, Norman MacLeod, and John Finley
      - Unidentified to Francis A. Fahy, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 2048)
      - Unidentified to "Nancy", 1974 (Box 54, Folder 2049)
      - Unidentified to Robert Taft, 1953 Jul 11 (Box 54, Folder 2050)
- Writings of Robert Fitzgerald, 1926-1984; Series II; 6.88; (17 boxes)
  Series II, Writings of Robert Fitzgerald, is organized into fourteen subseries: Articles and Essays, Autobiographical Writings, Criticism, Diaries, Edited Works, Lectures and Speeches, Obituaries and Tributes, Open Letters, Plays, Poetry, Reviews, School Work, Short Stories, and Translations.
  - ARTICLES AND ESSAYS
    - "Aiaia and Ithaca: Notes on a New Lowell Poem," draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1976 Sep (Box 55, Folder 2051)
    - "Dryden's Aeneid," reprint, Arion, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2052)
    - "Factual Memorandum on the Case of Ezra Pound," draft, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 55, Folder 2053)
    - "Faith & Modern Poetry," draft, typescript, corrected, [1952?] (Box 55, Folder 2054)
    - "The Future of Literature," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2055)
    - "Generations of Leaves," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1952 Jul?] (Box 55, Folder 2056)
    - "Hopkins Meeting 1," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2057)
    - "Insights From Antiquity," draft (Incomplete), typescript carbon, corrected, 1966 Mar 10 (Box 55, Folder 2057a)
    - "Introduction," draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy (Box 55, Folder 2057b)
    - ["Looking through the literature..."], typescript, corrected, 1978 Jan (Box 55, Folder 2058)
    - "Mirroring the Commedia"
      - Background Material, 1934-82, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2059)
      - Research Notes, 1934-69, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2060)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2061)
      - Draft, typescript and typescript photocopy, corrected (Box 55, Folder 2062)
      - Drafts, typescript and typescript photocopy (Box 55, Folder 2063)
      - Drafts, typescript photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2064)
      - Draft, typescript corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2065)
      - Postscript, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2066)
    - "My Own Pinch of Salt," printed version, The Nation, 1948 Jul 17 (Box 55, Folder 2067)
    - "A Note on Craft in Classic Verse," draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2068)
    - "A Note on Ezra Pound, 1955-56," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1955 Aug 15?] (Box 55, Folder 2069)
    - "Notes on Sherrington," draft, typescript (Box 55, Folder 2070)
    - "Painting," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2071)
    - "Politics and the Athenian Stage," draft, typescript (Box 55, Folder 2072)
    - "The Prose of Abraham," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1964 Aug 21 (Box 55, Folder 2073)
    - "Robert Frost, 1874-1963," draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2074)
    - "St. Thomas Aquinas," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1952 Apr (Box 55, Folder 2075)
    - "Sherman Comedy Well Acted and Well Directed," printed version, 1933 Aug 30
    - "A Springfield Memoir," draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2076)
    - "The Style that Does Honor," draft, typescript carbon, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 2077)
    - "Transition and Rennaisance," draft, typescript corrected (Box 55, Folder 2078)
    - "Unity of Command as it Functioned in the Pacific Ocean Areas in World War II," draft, typescript, 1945 Nov (Box 55, Folder 2079)
    - "Visitations of the Angel," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2080)
    - "War, Peace and the Churches," draft, typescript mimeograph, 1943 Jan 15 (Box 55, Folder 2081)
  - AUTOBIOGRAPHICAL WRITINGS
    - "Fifteen Years," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1954 May 31 (Box 55, Folder 2082)
    - "Rousseau and Romanticism," fragments, typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon (Box 55, Folder 2083)
    - ["Since I came home..."], draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2084)
    - "A Translator's Homer," draft, typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2085)
  - CRITICISM
    - Enlarging the Change
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon (Box 56, Folder 2086)
      - Drafts, prologue and Chapter 6, typescript carbon (Box 56, Folder 2087)
      - Draft, typescript photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2088-2089)
      - Draft, Chapter 4, typescript photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2090)
      - Draft, preface, typescript and typescript photocopy (Box 56, Folder 2091)
      - Lists of corrections, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2092)
      - Setting copy, [ca. 1984] (Box 56, Folder 2093-2094)
      - Galley proof, frontmatter and preface, 1985
  - DIARIES
    - "December 15, San Pedro," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2095)
    - ["My mother, my father, my brother..."], typescript, corrected, 1977 Jul 2 (Box 56, Folder 2095a)
    - ["Saturday, June 13..."], typescript, [ca. 1932-33] (Box 56, Folder 2096)
    - ["This morning I woke..."], holograph, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2097)
  - EDITED WORKS
    - The Collected Poems of James Agee
      - Background material, 1932-67, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2098)
      - Drafts, frontmatter, typescript photocopies, corrected, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 2099)
      - Draft, foreword, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2100)
      - Galley proof, 1968
      - Reviews, 1968-69 (Box 56, Folder 2101)
    - The Collected Short Prose of James Agee
      - Drafts, frontmatter, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2102)
      - Draft, "James Agee: A Memoir," typescript photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2103)
      - Draft, "James Agee: A Memoir," typescript carbon, corrected, 1968 May 1 (Box 57, Folder 2104)
      - Draft fragments, "James Agee: A Memoir," holograph, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 57, Folder 2105)
    - Mystery and Manners
      - Book jacket, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2106)
      - Reviews, 1969 (Box 57, Folder 2107)
  - LECTURES
    - "Am[erican] Acad[emy]," draft, outline and notes, typescript, 1976 Oct 13 (Box 57, Folder 2108)
    - "Choate alumni..." draft, typescript, corrected, 1976 May 15 (Box 57, Folder 2109)
    - "Danforth Talk: 26 February 79," draft, typescript, corrected, 1979 Feb 26 (Box 57, Folder 2110)
    - ["Education goes on throughout life..."], draft, typescript, corrected, 1982 Mar (Box 57, Folder 2111)
    - "Faith and Modern Poetry," draft, first page, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 57, Folder 2112)
    - "A First and in Every Respect..." draft, typescript carbon (2 copies), 1954 Mar 25 (Box 57, Folder 2113)
    - "For W.H.A. ..." draft, typescript, corrected, 1970 Mar 2 (Box 57, Folder 2114)
    - ["I became aware..."], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2115)
    - ["I will mention..."], draft, typescript, 1965 Mar 18 (Box 57, Folder 2116)
    - "The Man of the Renaissance," third draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2117)
    - ["My remarks will be..."], draft, typescript carbon, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 2118)
    - [On unidentified friend], outline and notes, holograph (Box 57, Folder 2119)
    - "Reception in Colloquim Room," draft, typescript, 1976 Mar (Box 57, Folder 2120)
    - "St. Thomas Aquinas - First Considerations," draft, typescript, 1952 Apr 1 (Box 57, Folder 2121)
    - "T. S. Eliot as of May First 1974," draft, typescript photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2122)
    - "The Things of the Eye," draft, typescript and typescript photocopy (2 copies), 1978 Mar 2 (Box 57, Folder 2123)
    - "Thinking of Robert Lowell: 1917-1977," draft, typescript corrected, photocopy, 1978 Mar 2 (Box 57, Folder 2124)
    - ["We might begin by trying..."]," draft, typescript, corrected, 1961 Jul 12 (Box 57, Folder 2124a)
    - "The World and the Ex-Schoolboy," draft, typescript carbon, 1942 (Box 57, Folder 2125)
    - "The World and "The Unapparent"," draft, typescript and typescript photocopy, 1976 May 16 (Box 57, Folder 2126)
    - ["Wystan Auden thought..."], draft, typescript, 1973 Oct (Box 57, Folder 2127)
  - OBITUARIES AND TRIBUTES
    - ["Chicago, April 29..."], draft, holograph, 1964 Apr 29 (Box 57, Folder 2128)
    - "Horace Gregory," draft, typescript carbon, 1982 Nov 10 (Box 57, Folder 2129)
    - "Prosody at Harvard," draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2130)
    - "W.H. Auden," draft, typescript, corrected, 1974 Oct (Box 57, Folder 2131)
  - OPEN LETTERS
    - "Fitzgerald describes interesting..." printed version, [ Illinois State Register ?], 1929 Aug 19 (Box 57, Folder 2132)
    - "Fitzgerald tells readers..." printed version, Illinois State Register, 1929 Sep 22 (Box 57, Folder 2133)
    - "Robert S. Fitzgerald..." printed version, Illinois State Register, 1929 Aug 25 (Box 57, Folder 2134)
  - OUTLINES AND NOTES
    - "A Book of Hours," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2135)
  - PLAYS
    - "The Death of the Strangler," draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1947 (Box 57, Folder 2136)
    - "The Strangler," drafts, typescript carbon, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2137)
  - POETRY
    - Collections
      - In the Rose of Time
        - Publicity, 1956 Nov 30
        - Reviews, 1957, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2138)
      - Poems
        - Publicity, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2139)
        - Reviews, 1936 (Box 57, Folder 2140)
      - Spring Shade
        - Reviews, 1973 (Box 57, Folder 2141)